Tibo Geenen

About me

Eager and motivated with experience in leadership roles. Not afraid of new experiences to further develop myself and become a more capable person and engineer. Passionate about the development of smart home automation and the energy systems of the future. Highly active member of Erasmus Student Network Leuven, a large student organisation focusing on the integration and self-development of international students.

Education

2019–2022 MSc Electrical Engineering, KU Leuven.

Option: Power Systems and Automation (grade: 75 %).

2020–2021 MSc Energy Engineering, Grenoble INP - ENSE3, Grenoble - France.

Option: Electrical Power Engineering (IEE) (grade: 85 %).

2016–2020 BSc Engineering Science, KU Leuven.

Major Electrical Engineering, Minor Materials/Business Engineering (grade: 67%).

2010–2016 **High school**, WICO Campus Sint-Jozef.

Option: Mathematics (8u) and science (grade: 84 %).

Experience

2022-present **President board of directors**, ESN Leuven.

Handling statutes and standing orders of a non-profit organisation, leading general meetings and overseeing daily board operations in cooperation with other members of the board of directors.

2019-present Cantus senior/cantor, ESN Leuven.

Leading over 30 cantus in English and Dutch with up to 200 participants per event.

2021–2022 **Finance manager**, *ESN Leuven*.

Keeping track of all the expenses and incomes, whilst making sure the organisation was financially stable and non-profit compliance regulations were followed. Consulting other board members in financial matters, negotiating with partners and using accounting software is part of this equation.

2020 & 2021 Process engineer, Polypreen NV.

Summer job to optimise the use of an industrial quilting machine by improving the design of CAD drawings to reduce the quilting time up to $50\,\%.$

2019–2020 Marketing manager, ESN Leuven.

Promoting all of the events in cooperation with a work group, whilst building a brand and providing the most reach possible.

2017–2019 **Scout leader**, Chiro Kerkhoven.

Leading the youngest and eldest group, whilst creating enjoyable activities, designing Chiro merchandise and promoting events.

Languages

Dutch: Native French: B2
English: C2 Danish: A1

Knowledge Area

Verilog: Good YAML: Excellent
Python: Good Inkscape: Excellent
MATLAB: Good OptronCAD: Excellent
Solid Edge: Good Microsoft Office: Excellent
Google App Scripts: Good Google Docs Editors: Excellent

Hobbies

Music: Guitar

Sports: Futsal, hiking, skiing & running Machinery: Laser cutting and 3D-printing

Home Automation: The use of open-source software for a DIY, local smart home

Accomplishments

- Well known amongst students in the engineering science community of Leuven for writing insightful study guides and course summaries.
- Drastically improving the flow of ticket sales and event boarding in a large student organisation by automating and simplifying user tasks, including enabling online sales and QR-ticketing.
- Significantly reducing overhead costs in a large student organisation by analysing sales data and selecting a more suited transactional provider.